

I am a self-motivated and energetic individual who has both higher education qualifications and work experience in the industry. I am also experienced in web & mobile developing, IoT, electronic,

IC programing, industrial automation, coordinating engineering projects.

CONTACT ME AT

- Gampaha city, Sri Lanka
- ashvinmendi@gmail.com
- in <u>@Ashvin</u>
- +9477 2185 783

Key Skills

- Ability to quickly learn new things within a short period.
- Have a strong team spirit and ability to work independently.
- Ensure tasks are completed within the estimated time

ASHVIN MENDIS

ashvinmendis/portfolio

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer

Tracified (Pvt) Ltd [Parent organization - 99X]

February 2022 - present

- Developed high quality dynamic and responsive web applications using Angular.
- Developed mobile application and Migrated ionic-V3 mobile applications to ionic-V6 using the Ionic framework, improved performance and stability.
- Employed techniques such as code splitting, reduce loading time, code minification and lazy loading.
- Skilled in Identifying and resolving software bugs in both web and mobile applications.
- Contributed to the backend development using node.js
- Continued the development of the IoT cold sensor project.

Technologies - Ionic, Angular, node-js, TypeScript, C++, Arduino

Associate Mechatronics Engineer - Urban Agri (Pvt) Ltd March 2021 - February 2022

- Engineered solution to production and process efficiency utilizing C++ in microcontroller programming.
- Utilized Blynk IoT platform to monitoring and control the production and plant condition.
- Build micro controller units and deployed automation systems for plant process and enhance productivity.
- Designed PCB and build custom hardware to meet management requirements.
- Conducted R&D activities to improve the production and plant quality.

Technologies: C++, Blynk IoT, Eagle CAD, Arduino, RaspberryPi

Hardware Trainee - Diesel & Motor Engineering PLC August 2019 - February 2021

- IR AC Controller: Designed PCB and programmed an IR AC controller which can control the air conditioners base on the room window state utilizing C++ and eagle.
- Power monitoring: Designed PCB and programmed utilizing C++ and eagle which can measure voltage, current & power and send values to MQTT server true WIFI and developed a user dashboard using Node-Red.
- Customized GPS unit's setting within GPS platform.
- Inspected the BYD full electronic car charging units of DIMO clients.

Technologies used - Arduino IDE, C++, Eagle, Proteus, Wi-Fi, IoT

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, SQL, HTML, CSS, SASS, C++,Python
- Frameworks: Angular, Ionic, react
- Version Controlling: GitHub, Jira
- IDE: Visual Studio, Arduino IDE, Atmel Studio
- Microcontrollers: ESP8266, ESP32, ATmega 328
- CAD Software: Proteus, Eagle CAD

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Master of Engineering (Hons) Mechatronics Engineering (2015-2019)
 Classification: Second class upper division. Awarded by University of Wolver Hampton UK.
- Certificate course in web developing design and development at NIBM. (2020) Designed and developed an Inventory web application by using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java Script, PHP, SQL technologies and presented.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

• Smart Glove - portfolio link

Achieved as best group project & won the gold medal

The Smart-glove is converted the sign languages into words(voice) via a mobile application. This creates the opportunity for the deaf persons to communicate with others. Developed the code for reading data from flex sensors and master-slave Bluetooth protocol connection utilizing C++.

• Pet Feeder Robot (Individual) - portfolio link

A robot capable of feeding pets through a mobile application. overcoming distance barriers and observing pets by a mini-camera. this robot can be fully controlled via a smartphone. the robot was programmed with Raspberry Pi and designed the GUI by Python. Designed the robot cheesy and the circuit (PCB) using eagle and solidwork.

NON RELATED REFEREES

Mr. Dileepa Jayathilake Co-Founder & CEO Tracified (Private) Limited +94776985444 dileepaj@tracified.com Mr. U.S.C Udawaththa
Plant Scientist
Urban Agri (Private) Limited
+94765476545
sampath.u@urbanagri.co